Walk to Section 5 Well we're going to talk about the project management foundations in this section.
We're going to really look at the big picture of project management.
This is a really important section to build a strong foundation on how the Pinback guide addresses project
management and what our project is and what a project is not.
We're going to talk about the temporary nature of projects how that also means the temporary nature
of teams.
But what about the deliverables the things that projects create.
We know that our projects create unique products or services or results but what about the temporary
nature of those.
Is that something that we consider as a project manager.
Or all those things temporary.
So we'll take a look at that in the section.
We're also going to talk about a new term re-imported term called business value.
So we to watch for that.
Talking about business value and how that affects project management.
We're going to look at why projects are created and how projects are selected and how does that relate
to business.
Now you are a really important topic.
We're going to define project management just a clear understanding of what is project management so
that we have a common understanding as we move through the remainder of the course.
And as you prepare to pass the PMP we need to be on the same page about what project management is.
We're going to look at the project management application areas the different fields of discipline where
project management works works everywhere and that will talk about the project lifecycle and as opposed
to the project management lifecycle.
So you want to pay attention to that.
All right a lot of information to cover.
Let's hop in here and knock it out and talking about these project management foundations.